<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Addy&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Addy&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Addy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/about/</guid>
      
        <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Addy
Just a student, a worker, and a Linux Enthusiast. I love metal, cat, linux, playing guitar, design, customizing desktop, more metal, reading, climbing mountain, fishing, watching movie, anime, and even more metal.
My favourite band is Dream Theater. Favourite GNU/Linux distro, Debian. Favourite movie director, Christopher Nolan. Favourite book, A Study in Scarlet. Favourite anime, Fullmetal Alchemist. Favourite album, Metropolis Part 2 : Scenes from a Memory.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Way of Configuring Ncmpcpp Music Player</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/configuring-ncmpcpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 21:34:30 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/configuring-ncmpcpp/</guid>
      
        <description>Introduction ncmpcpp is an mpd client. In short, it&amp;rsquo;s the frontend of mpd. The actual music player is mpd, but managing mpd with barehand is not possible. So, the most common way to control mpd is using ncmpcpp, to list the library, arranging the playlist, choosing the music, and other actions. mpd + ncmpcpp duo usually also paired with mpc for control.
info  Don&amp;rsquo;t forget that ncmpcpp is a terminal applications.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring URxvt to Make It Usable and Less Ugly</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/configuring-urxvt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 21:44:11 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/configuring-urxvt/</guid>
      
        <description>Introduction URxvt is a customizable terminal emulator forked from rxvt. Features of rxvt-unicode include international language support through Unicode, transparency, the ability to display multiple font types and support for Perl extensions. URxvt is one of the most popular terminal emulator in UNIX world, especially on Unixporn. It&amp;rsquo;s well known for being lightweight and riceable. But just like any other software in UNIX world, it&amp;rsquo;s ugly out of the box.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fish, The Friendly Interactive Shell</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/fish-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 18:16:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/fish-shell/</guid>
      
        <description>Introduction Most of GNU/Linux distros use bash as the default shell. But there are many aftermarket alternative of cli shell for it. And my favourite is fish, the friendly interactive shell. Some of my favourite features of fish are..
 Command suggestion, usually based on history. Hit right arrow or Ctrl+F to complete it.      Tab autocompletion, type several letter then hit Tab several times to see the options.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically Generate Openbox Applications Menu Using LXMenu Data</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/autogenerate-openbox-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 18:44:21 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/autogenerate-openbox-menu/</guid>
      
        <description>Introduction With regard to Openbox Menus, there are two types: static menus and dynamic menus. Dynamic menus also well known as pipe menu. In this article, I will explain how to use pipe menu to generate applications list easily. Because, writing our applications list manually to menu.xml will be exhausting. I use Debian by the way. So some command line in this article, like how to install packages, will use Debian way.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>