<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Addy&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Addy&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Addy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 19:44:16 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrot, A Simple Screenshot Taking App</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/scrot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 19:44:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/scrot/</guid>
      <description>Introduction According to Wikipedia, Scrot is a minimalistic command line screen capturing application. It allows substantial degree of flexibility by specifying parameters on command line, including the ability to invoke a third-party utility to manipulate the resulting screenshot.
When I installed Debian, I started from minimal install. So it didn&amp;rsquo;t come with any screenshot taking app by default, then I installed scrot. I just thought that scrot was quite enough for my necessity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Conky to Generate Lemonbar Statusline</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/lemonbar-conky/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 17:18:27 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/lemonbar-conky/</guid>
      <description>Introduction According to its GitHub page, Lemonbar (formerly known as bar) is a lightweight bar entirely based on XCB. Provides full UTF-8 support, basic formatting, RandR and Xinerama support and EWMH compliance without wasting your precious memory. I use Debian, and Lemonbar is available in Debian repository since Stretch, so just install it normally.
1  sudo apt-get install lemonbar   It just a bar. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t come with any module like in Polybar by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Fluxbox Configurations</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/my-fluxbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 10:45:56 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/my-fluxbox/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is an explanation about my Fluxbox configurations and how to use them. Fluxbox is my second window manager after Openbox. They are pretty similar because both are derived from Blackbox window manager. Some differences between Openbox and Fluxbox are..
 Fluxbox uses plain text of configuration files instead of XML. Fluxbox comes with a panel called Fluxbox Toolbar. The panel can contain taskbar, workspace indicator, workspace switcher, system tray, and clock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Several Custom Bitmap Fonts</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/bitmap-fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 20:56:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/bitmap-fonts/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is a post about several bitmap fonts I modify from M+, Tewi, Lemon, &amp;amp; Siji. At first I modify them because I can&amp;rsquo;t find any bitmap font that suitable for my personal preferences.
 I want a small bitmap font that can fit in 6x10 bounding box, but placed inside 6x12 bounding box for extra line spacing. I want extra line spacing for readability reason. I know I can add line spacing in URxvt configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dunst, A Simple And Lightweight Notification Daemon</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/dunst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 13:19:24 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/dunst/</guid>
      <description>Introduction According to the Dunst website Dunst is a lightweight replacement for the notification daemons provided by most desktop environments. It’s very customizable, isn’t dependent on any toolkits, and therefore fits into those window manager centric setups we all love to customize to perfection.
When I installed Debian, I start from minimal install. So, I don&amp;rsquo;t have any notification by default. Then I choose Dunst. If you already have other notification daemon and want to try Dunst, Just simply add Dunst to your autostart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Way of Configuring Ncmpcpp Music Player</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/configuring-ncmpcpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 21:34:30 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/configuring-ncmpcpp/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ncmpcpp is an mpd client. In short, it&amp;rsquo;s the frontend of mpd. The actual music player is mpd, but managing mpd with barehand is not possible. So, the most common way to control mpd is using ncmpcpp, to list the library, arranging the playlist, choosing the music, and other actions. mpd + ncmpcpp duo usually also paired with mpc for control.
info  Don&amp;rsquo;t forget that ncmpcpp is a terminal applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring URxvt to Make It Usable and Less Ugly</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/configuring-urxvt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 21:44:11 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/configuring-urxvt/</guid>
      <description>Introduction URxvt is a customizable terminal emulator forked from rxvt. Features of rxvt-unicode include international language support through Unicode, transparency, the ability to display multiple font types and support for Perl extensions. URxvt is one of the most popular terminal emulator in UNIX world, especially on Unixporn. It&amp;rsquo;s well known for being lightweight and riceable. But just like any other software in UNIX world, it&amp;rsquo;s ugly out of the box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fish, The Friendly Interactive Shell</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/fish-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 18:16:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/fish-shell/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Most of GNU/Linux distros use bash as the default terminal shell. But there are many aftermarket alternatives of cli shell for it. And my favourite is fish, the friendly interactive shell. Some of my favourite features of fish are:
 Command suggestion, usually based on history. Hit right arrow or Ctrl+F to complete it.      Tab autocompletion, type several letter then hit Tab several times to see the options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically Generate Openbox Applications Menu</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/autogenerate-openbox-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 18:44:21 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/autogenerate-openbox-menu/</guid>
      <description>Introduction With regard to Openbox Menus, there are two types: static menus and dynamic menus. Dynamic menus are also known as pipe menu. In this article, I will explain how to use pipe menu to generate applications list easily. Because, writing our applications list manually to menu.xml will be exhausting. I use Debian by the way. So some command line in this article, like how to install packages, will use Debian way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>