<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Urxvt on Addy&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/tags/urxvt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Urxvt on Addy&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Addy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 20:28:52 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/tags/urxvt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Use URxvt Daemon Mode to Decrease The Resources Usage</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/urxvtd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 20:28:52 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/urxvtd/</guid>
      <description>Introduction According to the manual page, URxvtd is same with URxvt but runs as a daemon that can open multiple terminal windows within the same process. Advantages of running a urxvt daemon include faster creation time for terminal windows and a lot of saved memory. The disadvantage is a possible impact on stability. If the main program crashes, all processes in the terminal windows are terminated.
How To Use Start The Daemon From my Urxvt Configurations, nothing needs to be changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring URxvt to Make It Usable and Less Ugly</title>
      <link>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/configuring-urxvt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 21:44:11 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://addy-dclxvi.github.io/post/configuring-urxvt/</guid>
      <description>Introduction URxvt is a customizable terminal emulator forked from rxvt. Features of rxvt-unicode include international language support through Unicode, transparency, the ability to display multiple font types and support for Perl extensions. URxvt is one of the most popular terminal emulator in UNIX world, especially on Unixporn. It&amp;rsquo;s well known for being lightweight and riceable. But just like any other software in UNIX world, it&amp;rsquo;s ugly out of the box.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>